Guide to the International Union of Operating Engineers Local 95 Records, 1946-1999 AIS.2003.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
International Union of Operating Engineers Local 95 Records
1946-1999
ULS Archives & Special Collections
International Union of Operating Engineers. Local 95 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.2003.01
36.25 Linear Feet (29 boxes)
International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 95 was chartered on March 24, 1902. Still in existence, the union represents operating engineers and stationary engineers that maintain large commercial, industrial, and institutional buildings in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. This collection contains membership application cards, correspondence, contracts and meeting minutes of International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 95.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William T. Cagney, Business Manager of Local 95, in 2003.
History
The International Union of Operating Engineers was founded in 1896 and is currently a member of the AFL-CIO. The International Union not only represents heavy equipment operators and mechanics, but also members of the public sector and service industry. International Union of Operating Engineers Local 95 was chartered on March 24, 1902 and represents operating engineers and stationary engineers that maintain large commercial, industrial, and institutional buildings in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
Previous Citation
International Union of Operating Engineers Local 95 Records, 1946-1999, AIS.2003.01, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
African American Construction Workers of Pittsburgh Photograph Collection, 1956-1987, AIS.2006.13, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains membership application cards, correspondence and meeting minutes of International Union of Operating Engineers Local 95. Also present is information regarding the National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers and the pursuit of state licensing legislation for boiler engineers. Contracts with various companies and buildings in Pittsburgh are also included.
Minutes (Administrative records); Correspondence; Membership cards; Contracts; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Steam engineers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor; National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers; International Union of Operating Engineers. Local 95 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Licensing of Engineers (Box 1, Folder 1)
- National Association of Power Engineers, Inc. Membership Packet (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Transcript, Annual Meeting of the National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers, Inc., April 30, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Power Safety International, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- National Institute for Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers Notebook, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Boiler and Stationary Engineers' Licensing, 1970, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Local 95 Training/Educational Trust Fund, 1987-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Boiler Engineers Act, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Examinations (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Proposed Legislation (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Licensing (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Training Program, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- New York City Licensing Regulations, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- IOUE Reports, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 16-19)
- Correspondence, 1971-1975, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
- Company Dues Structures, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
- Local 95 and National Institute for Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers Treasurer's Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 14-24)
- National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Pennsylvania National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers Licensee Data (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Certification of the Pennsylvania Board of the National Institute for the Unifrom Licensing of Power Engineers, March 4, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Engineer Training (Box 2, Folder 28)
- National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers Finances (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Independent Taxi and School Drivers Union, McGrogan Lawsuit (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Independent Taxi and School Drivers Union, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Independent Taxi and School Drivers Union, Crawford Unfair Labor Practice Charge (Box 3, Folder 3)
- John Orchowski, President of the Independent Taxi and School Drivers Union, Unemployment Compensation Claim (Box 3, Folder 4)
- John Orchowski, President of the Independent Taxi and School Drivers Union, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
- John Orchowski, President of the Independent Taxi and School Drivers Union, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- South Fayette Transition File (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Cash Book Disbursements, February 1989-November 1990 (Box 4, Volume 1-2)
- Finances (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Local 95 By-Laws, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
- Local 95 Elections, 1983, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
- Negotiations and Correspondence, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8-13)
- Financial Records, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- US Healthcare (Box 5, Folder 2)
- International Communications (Box 5, Folder 3)
- International Union (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Education Fund, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Duty of Fair Representation Cases (Box 5, Folder 6)
- National Institute for the Uniform Licensing of Power Engineers, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Northeast States Confernce of the International Union of Operating Engineers (Box 6, Folder 2)
- City of Pittsburgh (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Education Fund, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- International Communications, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Chlorofluorocarbons (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Shelley Elovitz, Esq. Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Local 95 Meeting Minutes, 1980-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1-16)
- Local 95 Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1989, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 17-19)
- Local 95 Building Fund Meeting Minutes (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Local 95 By-Laws, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- IUOE Trust Fund (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Seminars (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Members Survey (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Picnic, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Christmas Folder, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Parade (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Computer Centers of America (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Bridgeville Wage Tax (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Pequod Charters, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Allegheny County Labor (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Menzie Dairy Employees (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Computer File (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Shared Union Systems Inc. (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
- Penn Hills Earned Income Tax Rate 1.6% (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Christmas Letter, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 37-38)
- Spring Newsletter, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Sick List (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Paid Death Benefits (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Local 95 Retirees (Box 7, Folder 42)
- NABISCO Drug and Alcohol Policy (Box 7, Folder 43)
- General Correspondence File (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Agreement between Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic and JNESO-District Council 1, IUOE, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Item 1)
- Correspondence, 1990, 1993-1995 (Box 8)
- Membership Applicaton Cards, 1970-1993 (Box 9)
- Negotiations with Burns and Roe Services Corporation, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
- Health and Welfare (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Other Contracts (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Pittsburgh Legal Journal, October-December 1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Presbyterian Hospital, 1960s-1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Mercy Hospital, 1970s-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Burns Roe Construction Corporation, Paramus, NJ (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Arrott Building (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Remington Rand Building (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Webster Hall Hotel (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Jenkins Arcade Building (Box 11, Folder 7)
- City Products Corporation (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Kane Regional Centers, 1970s-1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Isley Dairy Co. (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Civic Building (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Model Coat and Apron Supply Co. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Civic Arena (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Contracts (Box 12-13)
- Allegheny Cold Storage Contract, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Allegheny County Contract, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Baldwin Courts Contracts (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
- Bellefield Boiler Contracts (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
- Benedum Center for the Performing Arts Contracts (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Borden's Dairy Contracts (Box 15, Folder 1)
- City of Pittsburgh Contracts, 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
- North Hills Passavant Hospital Contract, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Braun's Baking Co. Contract, 1983-1987 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Civic Arena Contracts (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Labor Disputes (Box 16, Folder 4)
- NLRB Case between South Side Hospital of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania and IUOE 95, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Brief for Labor Standards Association in Arbitration on Regular Wage Rates with Local 95 IUOE, December 10, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Joseph Horne Co. vs. IUOE 95 (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
- Check Book, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Magee Women's Hospital Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Mercy Hospital Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- One Mellon Center Contract (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Two Mellon Center Contract (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Three Mellon Center Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Muriel Street, US Steel Service Corp. Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- National Biscuit Co. Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- New Federal Cold Storage Contract, 1985-1989 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- OBAP Buildings Contract, 1983-1986 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- One Oliver Plaza Contract (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Oxford Center Contract (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Magee Women's Hospital Contracts, 1960s-1985 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
- Children's Hospital Contracts, 1974-1986 (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
- McKeesport Hospital, 1983-1985 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Chatham Center Contract, 1983-1986 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- C.R.H. Catering Co. Contract, 1985-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- City of Pittsburgh Contract, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Clark Building Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- D.L. Clark/Switzer Clark Contract, 1984-1989 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- CNG Towers Contract (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Commonwealth Building Contract, 1983-1986 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Equibank Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Fifth Avenue Place (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Frick Building Contract, 1983-1986 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- William Penn Hotel Strike, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Jerry Mason File, Liquid Carbonic (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Baldwin Court Apartments (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Leon E. Goodeloch (Box 20, Folder 4)
- McKeesport Hospital, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Local 95, Armour, Donald Rump (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Baldwin Court Contract, 1972-1983 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- PPG Place (Box 21, Folder 1)
- H.K. Porter Building Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Pitt Towers Contract, 1983-1986 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Pittsburgh Athletic Association Contract, 1982-1985 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Park Building Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Westin William Penn Hotel Contract, 1985-1988 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- US Steel Building Contract, 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Presbyterian Hospital Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Pittsburgh Press Contract, 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- 300 6th Avenue Building Contract, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- 301 Fifth Avenue Building Contract, 1983-1986 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- A.F. Management (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Alcoa Building (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Allegheny Building (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Allegheny County, 1960s-1980s (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
- Pitt Towers, 1960s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
- Pittsburgh Athletic Association, 1960s-1984 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Park Building, 1960s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- H.K. Porter Building, 1960s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Two Mellon Bank Center, 1960s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- US Steel Building, 1970s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- New Federal Cold Storage, 1960s-1984 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Allegheny Cold Storage, 1960s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Westin William Penn Hotel, 1960s-1985 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Three Mellon Bank Center, 1960s-1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- 441 Smithfield Building, 1960s-1985 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Equitable Energy, 1960s-1984 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
- Equibank, 1970s-1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- 301 5th Avenue Building, 1960s-1984 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- 300 6th Avenue Building, 1960s-1984 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Grant Building, 1960s-1984 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Northside Packing Co., 1960s-1985 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- National Biscuit Co., 1946-1985 (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
- Muriel Street, US Steel Service Corp., 1960s-1985 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Oxford Center, 1982-1985 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- One Oliver Plaza, 1960s-1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- OBAP Buildings, 1970s-1985 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- One Mellon Bank Center, 1983-1987 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Hilton Hotel (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
- Greengate Mall (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Grant Building (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Heinz Hall (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Health Center Service Corp. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Gateway Center (Box 26, Folder 7-9)
- Kane Regional Centers (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Kaufmann's Department Store (Box 26, Folder 11-12)
- IBM Building (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Housing Authority, City of Pittsburgh (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Horne's Department Store (Box 26, Folder 15)
- Liquid Carbonic (Box 26, Folder 16-17)
- Liberty Center (Box 26, Folder 18)
- Lawyer's Building (Box 26, Folder 19)
- Weekly Balance and Monthly Reports, June 1967-June 1983 (Box 27, Folder 1-16)
- Meeting Minutes, 1953-1979 (Box 27, Folder 17-37)
- Income Tax and Social Security, 1968-1982 (Box 28, Folder 1-15)
- Paid Pennsylvania Personal Income Tax, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 16)
- Paid City of Pittsburgh Occupational and Wage Taxes (Box 28, Folder 17)
- General Pension Fund (Box 28, Folder 18-20)
- Audit Reports (Box 28, Folder 21)
- Pennsylvania AFL-CIO (Box 28, Folder 22)
- Paid Federal Employment Quarterly Tax Return, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 23)
- National Labor Reports, 1962-1982 (Box 28, Folder 24-38)
- Union Dues Check Offs, 1986-1988 (Box 29, Folder 1-14)
- Central Pension Correspondence, 1971-1981 (Box 29, Folder 15-24)